제작 - 네이트 드라마 24 자막팀
http://club.nate.com/24
엄마, 그 차림으로 교회 갈 거예요?
아님 오늘 빨래하는 날이에요?
Hey, Mom, are you gonna wear that
to church or is it just laundry day?
너무 웃길 것 같죠?
Think about it.
아니, 병원에 응급상황이 생겼는데
일손이 부족하다는구나
No, there’s an emergency
at the hospital
and they’re really short-staffed.
미안한데, 난 오늘
교회 못 갈 것 같다
I’m sorry, I’m not gonna
make it to church today.
신난다! 교회 안 간다!
야구 경기 볼 수 있다!
Alright! No church! Hey, we
can watch the Brewers game.
좋았어! 로리는 핫도그 좀 굽고
우리는..
Yeah, sounds great. Laurie’ll cook
us up a couple of hot dogs, we’ll--
안돼! 웬 야구 경기, 왠 핫도그
신나는 날 같은 소리 말아요!
No! No Brewers,
no hotdogs, no nice day.
애들 책임지고 교회 보내세요
You’re gonna make sure
these kids get to church.
왜 꼭 교회 가야 돼요?
Why do we have to go?
이유야 수도 없다만
시간이 없구나
Well, I have a million
reasons and no time.
여기 1달러다
꼭 헌금해라!
Now, here’s a dollar --
for the offering.
잊지말고 찬송은 크고
자랑스럽게 하렴
And you remember:
you sing loud, you sing proud.
아빠는요? 아빠는 왜
안 가셔도 되는데요?
Hey, how about you? How come
you don’t ever have to go?
에릭
Eric
하느님과 나는 마음이 통했단다
God and I had
a heart to heart
남태평양에 내가 탔던 구축함이
침몰하는걸 보며 말이다
while I watched my destroyer
go down in the South Pacific.
우린 정말 잘 통한다
We’re real good.
넌 아니고
You’re not.
- 가라
- 알았어요
- Go.
- Okay.
이따 보자
Well, see ya.
난 친구들 만나러
볼링장 뒤에나 가봐야겠다
I’m going to go meet some
friends behind the bowling alley.
로리, 우리 교회가기로 했잖아
Laurie, we’re supposed
to go to church.
오, 우리 교회가기로 했잖아?
Oh, we’re supposed
to go to church.
기집애처럼 굴지 말고
나쁜 짓도 한번 해봐
Stop being such a little girl
and do something bad for once.
토퍼 그레이스 (에릭 포먼)
밀라 커니스 (재키 벅하트)
애쉬튼 커쳐 (마이클 켈소)
대니 메스털슨 (스티븐 하이드)
로라 프레폰 (도나 핀씨오티)
윌머 발더라마 (페즈)
데브라 조 러프 (키티 포먼)
커트우드 스미스 (레드 포먼)
타냐 로버츠 (미지 핀씨오티)
돈 스탁 (밥 핀씨오티)
리사 로빈 켈리 (로리 포먼)
That '70s Show 자막팀
영문자막 : 오흥민(echem@nate)
제작지원 : 김민경(paramount@nate)
번역 : 김현정(fuchs@nate)
That '70s Show 자막팀
영문자막 : 오흥민(echem@nate)
제작지원 : 김민경(paramount@nate)
2x23 Holy Crap!
May 01, 2000 on FOX
2x12 Eric's Stash
Jan 11, 2000 on FOX
에릭, 너 오늘 교회 안 갔네?
So, Eric, I see you’re
not in church today.
그래
Uh, no, now that I’m
not a virgin anymore,
난 총각딱지 뗐잖아
그래서 인제 기도할 게 없어
there’s really nothing left to pray for.
인생이 엿같다
Hey, man. My life sucks. Ever since
Jackie left, I’m no good at pinball.
재키한테 채인 뒤로는
핀볼도 안돼
너 원래 핀볼 못했잖아
You were never good at pinball.
재키가 없어서
좋은 점을 생각해 보자
Let’s look at the bright
side of not having Jackie.
우선
First,
재키가 없다
no Jackie.
둘째, 재키랑 있을 땐 절대 못하던 걸
인제 다 할 수 있다
Second, now you can do all the
things that you could never do
when you were with her, man.
Which was, at last count, everything.
이를 테면 최소한..
전부 다!
니 말이 맞아!
Oh, man, you’re right!
재키는 내가 바람도
못 피게하고, 또..
You know, Jackie never ever
wanted me to like, cheat on her,
수염도 못 기르게 했어
진짜 기르고 싶었는데
or, or grow a beard.
And I always wanted to.
인제 길러도 되겠다
And now I can let this grow out.
나도 길러도 돼?
May I grow one, too?
글쎄, 페즈. 우리 둘이
같이 수염을 기른다고?
I don’t know, Fez. The two of
us growing beards together?
그거 좀 기집애들 같지 않냐?
Isn’t that kinda girlie?
같이 기르면
털이 더 많아지잖아!
Well, I just figure,
the more the hairier.
이런 멍청한 것들 사이에서
내가 뭘 하겠어!
Oh, I am surrounded by idiots.
교회 다녀온 척 하려면
뭐부터 해야 될 지 알아?
Hey, you know what might make
our little church ploy work better?
단추부터 좀 잠궈
If you’d button your shirt.
머리 속에 이게 뭐지?
Oh, and, hey, what’s in your hair?
담배꽁초잖아
Oh, a cigarette butt.
이런! 인제 아스팔트 위에선
다시는 안 할 거야!
Ugh! That’s the last time
I make out on asphalt.
여기들 있구만
Oh, there they are.
꼬마 천사들이 집에 왔구나
교회는 어땠니? 설교는 좋았어?
My little angels are home. How
was church? Good sermon?
좋았어요. 예수님 말씀은
정말 지혜로우신 것 같아요
Oh, you know, fine. Jesus
said something really wise.
사람들이 다
"오 예수님" 그랬다니까요
People said, “Oh, that Jesus.”
이제 그분 말씀대로
살아 보려구요
And now we go and try
to live our lives that way.
두마리의 사기꾼처럼 말이지?
You mean like a
couple of big, fat liars?
그래, 마당에서 밥이랑
마주쳤는데
Yeah, I ran into Bob
out in the driveway.
너희가 교회에 안 왔었다고
하더구나
And he told me you
weren’t at church.
이래서 밥 아저씨가 싫다니까!
God, I hate Bob!
전 갈려고 했어요, 아빠
근데 에릭이 태워다 주질 않았어요
I tried to go, Daddy, but
Eric wouldn’t give me a ride.
어이, 막달라 마리아
목에 붙은 껌이나 떼셔
Hey, Mary Magdalene,
there’s some gum on your neck.
우리 애들이 이런 짓을 하다니
믿을 수가 없구나
I can’t believe that my
own children would do this.
엄마, 날씨가 너무 좋잖아요, 그래서..
Mom, I mean, it’s
such a nice day, and ..
항상 말씀하시던 신선한 공기를
좀 쏘이고 싶었어요
we wanted to get some of that fresh
air you’re always telling us about.
야, 죄인 주제에 입은 살아가지고
Hey, nobody likes a
smart-mouth sinner.
당신이 확실히 챙겼으면
이런 일이 안 생겼죠
You know, this
wouldn’t have happened
if someone had made sure his
children had gotten to church.
뭐, 이봐..
Well, hey...
젠장..
damn.
알았어, 앞으로 너희 둘은 교회에
가도록 해라. 이건 명령이야
Alright, from now on, you kids are
going to church. That’s an order.
- 아~ 아빠...
- 됐어요, 있잖아요?
- Oh, Dad...
- Okay, you know what?
애들한테 강제로 시키면 안 되죠
We shouldn’t have to force them.
애들은 다 컸으니까
본인 의지대로 할 수 있어요
They’re almost grown up.
They can make up their own minds.
정말요?
Really?
그럼
Sure.
정 너희가 하느님께 등을 돌려서
If you want to turn
your backs on God,
불지옥에서 영원히 허우적거리고
싶거든 알아서들 하렴
and spend eternity doing laps in a
lake of fire, well, that’s your choice.
일주일 후
에릭네 지하실
Forman Basement
One Week Later
얘들아?
Guys, huh? What do
you think of the beard?
내 턱수염 어떠냐?
일주일 기른 거 치곤 괜찮지, 응?
Yeah, it’s not bad
after just a week, huh?
바보같은 짓이야
부랑자 같잖아
I think it’s stupid.
You look like a hobo.
너 미쳤구나
You’re crazy.
아니, 너 부랑자 같이 보여
No, you look like a hobo.
- 미친 것!
- 부랑자!
- Crazy!
- Hobo!
어쨌든 난 맘에 들어
터프해 보이잖아?
Yeah, well, I like it.
I think it looks rugged.
덥수룩해질 거니까 두고 봐
Look how thick it’s coming in, huh.
안녕?
Hello.
우와, 페즈. 턱수염 죽인다
Wow, Fez, that’s a nice beard.
일단 제대로 자라면
진짜 죽일걸?
It will be. Once it really comes in.
마이클 바보같아 보이지 않니?
Doesn’t Michael look stupid?
제대로 자라지도 않아 가지구
누더기 같잖아
I mean, it’s not even growing
in right. It’s all patchy.
하하하, 빈약한 누더기같으니!
Aw, poor Patchy.
됐어, 난 인정 못해
Alright, I don’t have to take this.
오, 누더기가 열받았구나
Oh, now we made Patchy upset.
잘 가, 누더기야
- Bye, Patchy.
- So long, Patchy.
나 누더기가 보고 싶어
I miss Patchy.
턱수염 기르니까
마이클 섹시하지 않니?
Doesn’t Michael look
hot with that beard?
그러니까, 터프하고 반항아같잖아
I mean, it’s all rough and forbidden.
너 아까는 바보같아 보인다며
I thought you said
Kelso looks stupid.
어떻게 걔한테 맘에 든다고 말하니?
Well, I can’t tell him I like it.
I hate his guts.
뻔뻔스러운 꼴을 어떻게 보려고
그치만 저 인간
섹시해 지니까 더 미워
But I hate him even more
now that he’s so hot.
저 섹시한..
That hot, bearded jerk.
턱수염 바보
내 턱수염은 어때?
What about my beard?
거기 계란 묻었다!
It has egg in it!
로리, 뭐하는 거니?
10분 후면 예배가 시작될 거야
Laurie, what are you doing?
Church starts in ten minutes.
엄마, 난 안 가요
Mom, I’m not going.
뭐?
What?
에릭도 안 간대요
Well... Eric’s not going either.
무슨 소리! 갈거야
Oh, of course he is.
네? 엄마, 저번에 분명..
What? No, uh, you know, I thought,
알아서 하라고 하셨잖아요
Mom I thought you
said we had the choice.
그래서?
Uh-huh...
그래서 전 "안 간다"로 선택했어요
And I chose “no.”
그치만, "간다"가
간발의 차로 이등이었어요
But, uh, “yes” was a close second.
도저히 이해할 수가 없구나
You know, I don’t
understand this at all.
교회에 가기 싫은 정당한 이유를
하나만 대보렴
You give me one good reason
why you don’t want to go to church.
- 거긴 넘 더워요
- 거긴 넘 지루해요
- It’s hot.
- It’s boring.
- 음악이 넘 후져요
- 목사가 넘 못 생겼어요
- The music sucks.
- The pastor’s ugly.
- 넥타이 매야 되잖아요
- 브라 해야 되잖아요
- I have to wear a tie.
- I have to wear a bra.
그만!
Enough!
하이드는요?
쟤는 안 가도 되나요?
What about Hyde.
I mean, he doesn’t have to go.
난 유대교와 기독교의 교리를
존중하고
While I respect the
Judeo Christian ethic,
뿐만 아니라 동양철학도 존중하고
as well as the Eastern
philosophies and,
물론 마호메트의 가르침도 존중하지만
of course, the teachings
of Mohammed,
조직화된 종교는 역사상 자신들의
무수한 잔혹행위를 정당화하기 위해
I find that organized religion
has corrupted those beliefs
그들의 믿음조차 왜곡하고
있다는 걸 알게 됐어
to justify countless atrocities
throughout history.
그러니까 내가 교회가 간다면
난 위선자가 되는 거지
Were I to attend church,
I’d be a hypocrite.
좋아, 잘 들어
Okay, you know what?
난 5분 후에 출발할 건데, 너희들이
옳은 결정을 내릴 거라 믿는다
I am leaving in five minutes, and I’m
sure you will make the right decision.
아냐, 네가 옳은 결정을
내릴거라 믿는다
No, you’ll make the right decision.
그리고 네가 로리를 끌고 와
And you drag her with you.
교회 의자에 나 혼자 앉아
있는 일은 없겠지?
Something tells me that I won’t
be sitting in that pew alone.
이봐요, 키티
핀씨오티 가족은 다 왔는데
Hey, Kitty, the Pinciottis are all here.
포먼네 나머지 선수들은 어딨어요?
Where’s the rest of team Forman?
그게.. 오늘은 저 혼자에요
Oh, I’m, I’m, all alone today.
혼자라구요?
에구, 엄청 쪽팔리겠다
All alone?
Ick, that’s just embarrassing.
어떻게 그럴 수가 있죠?
That’s a shame.
누군가 회개해야 할 놈이 있다면
Because if there’s anyone
who has some confessing to do,
그건 더럽고 추악한
댁네 아들놈인데요
it’s that dirty, dirty son of yours.
실례해유, 아줌니
여기 자리 있슈?
‘Scuze me, ma’am,
is this seat taken, man?
보면 몰라요?
Do you see anyone?
난 여기가 참 좋아유
I love it here, man.
저 위에 아저씨는
이야기도 해 주구유
The guy up there tells stories,
that guy wails on the organ,
저 아저씨는
오르간도 연주해 주구유
목청껏 노래해도 되잖유
you can sing as loud as you want.
거의 신의 은총 아니것슈?
It’s almost a religious experience.
천국이 딱 여기 같을 거 같아유
안 그래유?
I kind of think this is what heaven
is going to be like, you know?
그래도, 천국에선 공짜술도 주겄쥬?
Plus, they’ll have an open bar.
이쪽입니다
Right this way.
신발 털고 들어가세요
Wipe your feet, please.
죄송하지만, 플래쉬는
터뜨릴 수 없습니다
Sorry, no flash photography.
다음 분!
Next!
오, 저희에요
포먼 가족 네 사람이요
Oh, that’s us.
Forman, party of four.
죄송합니다
못 들여보내 드리겠네요 / 네?
- Sorry, I can’t let you in.
- What?
저희 전부 다요?
All of us or just Laurie?
아니면 로리만요?
여러분 전부 다요
안녕, 로리?
All of you. Hi, Laurie.
키티, 가족들 데리고 교회에 가셨으면
됐는데.. 안 그러셨잖아요
Kitty, if you’d only gone to church
with your family... but you didn’t.
자, 떨어집니다!
So, down you go.
이건 할 때마다 재밌다니까!
I love that gag.
좀 비켜주시겠어요?
Step aside, would you, please?
다음 분!
Next!
안녕하시오, 안넝하시오
안뇽하시오, 지나갑시다
Hey there, ho there,
hi there, coming through.
지금 장난하시는 거죠?
Oh, you have got to be kidding me.
어쩌겠어요?
저분들은 교회에 다닌 걸요
What can I do?
They went to church.
여기 20달러 받고
앞자리로 좀 잡아주겠소?
Here’s twenty.
Can you find us a seat up front?
됐어, 못 참아!
밥을 패줘야겠어 / 여보!
Alright, that’s it, I’m
kicking Bob’s ass. / Red!
여보, 우린 어차피 지옥갈 거잖아
Well, Kitty, we’re
going to Hell anyway.
설마 그럴려구
Well, that’s just not gonna happen.
고마워, 친구
Thanks, man.
교회는 어땠어?
How was church?
잘 됐어요! 내가 우리 죄많은 아이들을
어떻게 해야 할지 알아 냈어요
Great! I figured out what to
do with our sinner children.
여보, 우리 아이들은 괜찮아
Kitty, our kids are fine.
- 오, 정말요? 그럼 로리는 왜....
- 이봐, 이봐
- Oh, really? So why is Laurie--
- Hey, hey.
애들 잘못을 말하자는 거면
에릭한테 집중하자구
If we’re going to start taking shots
at our kids, let’s focus on Eric.
바로 그거에요
걔의 잘못을 바로 잡아줘야 돼요
Well, that’s the point:
he needs to learn right from wrong.
걔가 나쁜 길로 빠지지
않았으면 좋겠어요
I don’t want him turning bad.
여보, 걔는 나쁜 길로 빠지지 않을 거야
Kitty, I don’t think Eric’s gonna turn
bad. He’s too much of a panty-waist.
그러기에는 그 자식 너무 새가슴이거든
걔들을 왜 두둔하는 지 알아요
I know why you’re
defending them, Red.
당신이 모범을 보이지 못하는 게
찔려서 그러죠?
You feel guilty because
you set a bad example.
여보, 난 교회 가잖아
Hey, I go to church. Just not
during televised sporting events.
TV에서 스포츠 중계할 때만 안가는 거지
당신도 알다시피, 내가 탔던 구축함이
남태평양에 침몰할 때....
You know, Kitty, when my destroyer
went down in the South Pacific--
또 그 소리, 지겨워요
Oh, blah, blah, blah.
좋아, 만약 애들이 나 때문에 교회에
안 가는 거라면 나도 갈께
Fine. If I thought the kids weren’t
going because of me, I’d go.
다행히도, 그건 아닌 것 같으니
난 안 가도 되겠지만 말야
Fortunately, I don’t think that.
So I'm not going.
그건 그렇고 말이에요, 여보
Well, that’s all well and good, Red,
애들이 교회에 안 가겠다니까
교회를 애들한테 갖다 주려구요
but since they won’t go to church,
I’m bringing the church to them.
데이브라는 젊은 목사님한테
저녁식사에 와 달라고 부탁드렸어요
I’ve asked Dave, the church youth
minister, to come here to dinner.
그랬더니 "당빠죠" 라던데요
And he said, “Groovy.”
좋은 생각같군
That sounds like a great idea.
정말 그렇게 생각해요?
You really think so?
- 나는 거기 있을 필요 없겠지?
- 네
- I don’t have to be there, right?
- No.
정말 좋은 생각이야
Sounds like a great idea.
너 꼭 교회에 가야 돼, 에릭
하느님은 모든 것을 보고 계시거든
You should really go to church, Eric.
‘Cause God, he sees everything.
그래서 나도 착하고 순수하게 살잖아
That’s why I live my
life good and pure.
켈소, 넌 두 여자한테
양다리 걸쳤었잖아
Kelso, you were dating
two girls at the same time.
그래, 그치만 하느님도 그건 못 보셨어
Yeah, but God didn’t see that.
난 내 밴 안에 있었거든
그 분도 납판은 투시 못하셔
I was in my van,
and he can’t see through lead.
난 종교논쟁에 끼어들고 싶지는 않아
I don’t want to get into
a religious argument,
그치만 우리 신이 너네 신 엉덩이를
걷어차 줄 수 있을껄
but my God could
kick your God’s ass.
신은 죽었어, 얘들아
God is dead, man.
It said so in “Time” magazine.
"타임"지에도 그렇게 나왔어
아녀, 저번에 버스 탔을 때
신 옆에 앉은 적 있단 말여
No, man, I sat next to
God once on the bus.
나헌티 삶의 의미를 말씀해주시고는
쁘레첼을 주셨어
He told me the meaning of life
and then he gave me a pretzel.
삶의 의미가 뭐래요?
So, what’s the meaning of life, man?
어.. 그려
Uh... Yeah, I guess I
should have written it down.
적어둘껄 그랬구먼
그래도 쁘레첼은 진짜 맛있었어
But it was a good pretzel, man.
어쩌면 인생은 무상한 걸지도 몰라?
Maybe this life doesn’t
even matter, you know?
우린 여기 존재하지 않는 걸 수도 있고
Maybe we’re not even here.
아냐, 어쩌면 나는 여기 있는데
너희가 존재하지 않는 걸 수도 있어
Or, no, maybe I’m
here but you’re not.
여보세요?
Hello?
하느님이 하신 일 중에
제일 잘 하신게 뭔 줄 알아?
You know what the best
thing God ever did was?
유방
Boobs.
그래, 그리고 하느님이 말씀하시길
"유방이 있으라"
Yes. And God said,
“Let there be boobs.”
그러자 유방이 생겨났지
And then there were boobs.
야, 만약에 하느님이 전능하시면
Hey, if God is all-powerful,
당신조차도 못 들 정도로
크게 유방을 만들 수 있으실까?
can he make a boob so
big that even he can’t lift it?
정말 좋은 질문이야, 친구
That’s a good question, man.
담에 버스타면 물어봐 주께
I’ll ask him next time I’m on the bus.
마이클 온다
너무 멋있지 않니?
Oh, my God, here comes Michael.
Isn’t he gorgeous?
재키! 쟤는 바람피우고
사기친 개야, 기억 안나?
Jackie! He’s the dog that lied
and cheated on you, remember?
좋아, 좋아
계속 그런 식으로 말해줘
Good, good.
Keep saying stuff like that
내가 쟤 품에 뛰어들지 못하게 말야
so that I don’t throw myself at him.
이런, 알았어
Gee, I’ll try.
안녕, 지나갈께
Oh, hey. Excuse me.
- 안녕, 마이클
- 이 정신나간 양다리쟁이야
- Hey, Michael.
- You sub-mental, twotiming dog.
안녕, 재키
Hey, Jackie.
- 어디가는 거야?
- 넌 거짓말쟁이, 사기꾼, 양아치야
- So, where are you off to?
- You lying, cheating, dirtbag jerk.
'허브'에 가는 길이야
수염도 기르고 해서 말야..
Well, I’m just going to go over to The
Hub. Grow my beard, you know...
수염 산뜻해
Well, that’s neat.
거기는 바람피우고 거짓말해서
지 여자친구 상처입힌 쓰레기도 받아준대?
So, they allow scumwads in there
who cheat on their girlfriends
and lie to them and
break their hearts?
어.. 아마 그럴껄?
Um... I guess so, yeah.
어떤 애들은 하느님이 썰렁하다고
생각들 하는 거 같은데
Now, I know some of the kids
today think God’s a real downer,
사실 분위기 업시키는 분이셔
but the truth is, he’s an upper.
들어보렴
And let me tell you something:
LSD나 PCP보다
훨씬 좋은 약이 있는데
here’s a much better drug than
LS- D or P-C-P. I get high on G-OD.
난 GOD에 정말 뿅 간단다
숫총각
Virgin.
감기 조심해라!
Bless you.
근데, 전 왜 여기 있어야 돼요?
Okay, why am I here?
왜냐면 넌 내 보살핌을 받는
어린 영혼이니까, 냉큼 앉지 못해
Because you’re a young soul
in my care. Now, sit, dammit.
죄송해요, 목사님
Sorry, Dave.
나 숫총각 되게 좋아하는데
I have a soft spot for virgins.
도전해 보고픈 의욕이 솟구쳐요!
Because they’re such a challenge.
종교도 멋지단다
Religion can be cool.
사실, 예수님은 유명한 반항아랑
비슷한 면이 아주 많으시지
In fact, Jesus was a lot
like another famous rebel.
폰지 말야
70년대 드라마'Happy Days'의 주인공
Fonzie.
다만, 폰지가 "에이~!" 할 대목에서
예수님은 "에이~멘!" 하신단다
But where Fonzie says, “Ayyy!”
Jesus says “Ayy-men!”
예수님도 폰지처럼 주크박스를
한방 쳐서 작동시킬 수 있을까요?
But, Dave, could Jesus start
a jukebox just by hitting it?
가능하실거야
다만 그분은 뭘 때리는 걸 싫어하셔
He could. But Jesus
doesn’t like to hit anything.
예수님도 상어 등에 올라타고
수상스키 타신 적 있으실까요?
Did he ever water-ski over a shark?
좋아, 성경에 대해서는 질문 없니?
Okay, does anyone have
a question about the Bible?
저요!
I do! Do you have your own place?
혼자 사세요?
얘기는 그만하고
노래를 부르는 게 어때요?
Hey, you know what? How ‘bout we
just stop talking and sing songs?
♪예수님이 나는 참 좋아
예수님이 나는 참 좋아♪
♪ Jesus is just alright with me.
Jesus is just alright with me. ♪
다 같이!
♪ Jesus is just alright with me.
Jesus is just alright, oh yeah. ♪
Jesus is just alright with me. ♪
이제 뭘 그렸는지 한 번 봅시다
Okay, let’s look at your pictures.
키티, 하느님을 생각하면
뭐가 떠오르시죠?
Kitty, what do you see
when you think of God?
오, 아주 좋아요
살아있는 것 같네요
Oh, that’s nice. Very lifelike.
그분께서 우리가 다 같이 교회가는 걸
흐뭇하게 지켜보고 계세요
See? He’s looking down fondly
on all of us going to church.
스티븐?
Steven?
아주 좋아. 넌 하느님을 생각하면
예수님이 떠오르나 보구나
Oh, very good. I see, when you
think of God, you see Jesus.
아뇨
이건 에릭 크랩튼이에요
No, man. It’s Clapton.
세상에, 나도 크랩튼 그렸는데
Oh, my God, man,
I drew Clapton, too.
좋아, 잘했다. 로리?
Okay, cool. Laurie?
전 당신을 위해 특별한 걸 그렸어요
나중에 혼자만 보세요
I drew a special picture just for you.
Look at it later, when you’re alone.
전 10 원 페어에요
I’ve got a pair of tens.
우리 믿음의 식구들은
그걸 '사도 페어'라고 하지
Or, as we say in “Religious
Rummy,” a pair of Apostles.
오, 저는 잭, 퀸, 킹이 있어요
Ooh, I have a jack,
a queen, and a king.
요셉, 마리아, 예수님 말씀이시죠?
You mean, a Joseph,
a Mary and a Jesus.
와우, 그럼 이 패는 무적이겠네요
Wow, I bet that’s
gonna be hard to beat.
그럼요, 키티
That’s so true, Kitty.
로리는 뭘 가졌는지 보자
Let’s see what Laurie’s got.
6...
Six...
six...
six.
아주 멋진 저녁이었습니다
나중에 교회에서 뵙죠
Well, thank you all for the lovely
evening. I’ll see you at the church.
오, 마이클?
Oh, Michael...?
오, 마이클
Oh, Michael.
일주일 후
에릭네 거실
Forman Living Room
One Week Later
- 엄마, 왜요!
- 에릭, 로리. 교회갈 준비 해라
- Mom, Hey!
- Eric, Laurie, get ready for church.
잠깐만요. 저희더러
알아서 하라고 하셨잖아요
Wait a second. I thought
you said it was our choice.
너희가 간다고 했으면
너희들 뜻대로 했겠지
Well, when you choose
to go, it’ll be your choice.
목사님 왔을 때 보니까
너희는 교회에 가야 돼
Coming on to the youth
minister. You need church!
엄마, 왜 이러시는 거예요?
Mom, why are you doing this?
이유가 있어야 되니? 이게 옳고
난 너희 엄마야, 그러니까 움직여
I don’t have to have a reason.
It’s right, I’m your mother, now move.
그치만 공정치 못하잖아요
왜 우리만 교회에 가야 돼요? 그러니까..
But it’s not fair. I mean, why do we
have to go to church? I mean...
아빠도 안 가시잖아요
Dad doesn’t go.
아하! 아하! 아하! 아하! 아하!
A-ha a-ha a-ha a-ha a-ha!
좋아요, 여러분
포먼 가족 모두 교회에 가는 거예요
Come on, everybody,
the Formans are going to church!
꼭 그렇게 같이
죽어야 속이 시원하냐?
You had to throw me under
the bus with you, didn’t ya?
아주 자-알 했다, 에릭
Well, nice going, Eric.
그래, 아주 자-알 했다
이제 브라해야 되잖아
Yeah, nice going.
Now I have to put on a bra.
하나님이 날 미워하시는 거야
God hates me.
♪ 오, 하나님
제게 세가지 소원이 있습니다 ♪
♪ Oh, Dear Lord,
Three things I pray... ♪
♪ 당신을 더 확고히 믿게 하시고 ♪
♪ To see thee more clearly... ♪
♪ 당신을 더 다정히 사랑하게 하시고 ♪
♪ Love thee more dearly... ♪
♪ 당신을 더 가까이서 따르게 하소서 ♪
♪ Follow thee more nearly, ♪
♪ 매일 매일..
매일 매일 매일 매일 매일 ♪
♪ Day by day...
Day by day by day by day by day ♪
번역수정 : 김찬미 (husseyttl@nate)
최종수정 : 김현정(fuchs@nate)
자유배포 / 수정금지
네이트 드라마 24 자막팀
http://club.nate.com/24
자유배포 / 수정금지
네이트 드라마 24 자막팀
http://club.nate.com/24